Welcome to the Diploma in Citizen Participation for the Fight against Climate Change.
This program is an invitation to be an active part of the solution, to become an agent of change in your community.
Here, you will strengthen your knowledge and skills in mechanisms and strategies that foster a citizenship committed to its environment and its future.
This Diploma is a fundamental part of the EPAI project.
Intelligent personal learning environments, funded by the European Union with code EPI 1010-82868.
It offers you an innovative and high-quality learning experience.
Together we will build a sustainable future, connecting with other citizens passionate about participation and positive impact.
11 prestigious universities from Latin America and Europe.
are part of this effort to offer you a cutting-edge learning experience.
Among the eight participating Latin American universities are the Autonomous Universities of Aguas Calientes and Yucatán in Mexico, the
American and Technological La Salle Universities of Nicaragua, the National Federico Villarreal and Catholic Santa María Universities of Peru.
and the National Pedagogical University and the Rafael Núñez University Corporation of Colombia.
The latter acting as the general coordinator of the project.
From Europe, we have valuable participation from the Nova University of Lisbon, Portugal, the National Distance Education University (UNED) of Spain, and the
Technological University of Bucharest in Romania.
The EPAI project addressing
the global need to fight against climate change that impacts all people and all living beings on the planet.
For us humans, in all our areas of development, it creates the opportunity to be agents of change, contributing to training in strategies that promote
active citizen participation from different levels of the fight against this phenomenon of climate change.
The general objective of this diploma is to train
agents of change with competencies and citizen participation in environmental sustainability through active methodologies and the strategic use of digital tools.
Through project-based learning, participants will be trained to understand the fundamentals of climate change, analyze mechanisms of citizen participation that
favor environmental sustainability
through successful cases and initiatives.
Develop practical activities in the application of digital tools and collaborative strategies with local governments and NGOs for climate action.
Design and implement effective communication and environmental education strategies that raise awareness and mobilize the entire community around the actions we can
develop to mitigate climate change.
in evaluating public policies and environmental management routes that can be strengthened and with which we can help strengthen the capacity and incidence
of citizens in actions against this phenomenon.
Progressively build a differential project, formulating a local or global action plan that involves the community in mitigation and climate adaptation activities.
It will also promote the development of competencies such as adopting a sustainability-centered mindset, that sustainability that we must make livable in our daily
lives with each of our actions, recognizing that we have an individual but also collective responsibility to protect and restore that natural environment at the
local and global level.
and also to inspire others through the actions we carry out.
Also to understand the repercussions of climate change on biodiversity and on the living conditions of plants and animals and also on the
quality of water and air.
Develop related capacities, develop capacities that are related to the ability to process and use knowledge and information
of transversal importance and that favor our formation as citizens aware of environmental sustainability.
And finally, that we contribute to the generation of an awareness in which we recognize that the response to climate change mitigation lies in each of us, that we are
citizens of the world, local citizens and global citizens, where an excellent starting point
is to take this diploma, a diploma in which experts will be our teachers.
Thank you very much.